<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.mrshell.PiLauncher</id>
  
  <name>PiLauncher</name>
  
  <summary>Minecraft Launcher for Gamepad</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_CN">专为手柄设计的 Minecraft 启动器</summary>

  <developer id="com.mrshell">
    <name>MrShell</name>
  </developer>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <description>
    <p xml:lang="zh_CN">PiLauncher 是一款为游戏手柄和掌机量身定制的 Minecraft 启动器。它拥有为主机式体验优化的全屏用户界面，让你可以轻松地使用手柄管理、配置和运行你的 Minecraft 游戏实例。</p>
    <p>PiLauncher is a Minecraft launcher tailored for gamepads and handheld consoles. It features a full-screen, console-like user interface optimized for controller inputs, allowing you to easily manage and launch your Minecraft instances.</p>
    <ul>
      <li xml:lang="zh_CN">完全支持手柄操作，提供沉浸式大屏体验。</li>
      <li>Full gamepad support for an immersive large-screen experience.</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh_CN">自动识别和配置手柄相关模组。</li>
      <li>Automatic detection and configuration of gamepad-related mods.</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh_CN">极简且现代化的实例和模组管理。</li>
      <li>Minimalist and modern instance and mod management.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.mrshell.PiLauncher.desktop</launchable>

  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
  </categories>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.1.29" date="2026-04-23">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">局域网同步功能上线与实例部署稳定性优化</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 实现局域网设备自动发现、配对与信任管理服务，支持跨设备实例与存档投送。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 新增后台游戏时长统计服务，支持多设备间游玩数据实时同步。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 重构资源中心，实现 Mod 库深度搜索、依赖自动解析与一键安装功能。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 全新「衣柜」皮肤预览模态框，支持 3D 渲染与更细致的皮肤自定义。</li>
          <li>[优化] 引入“原子化部署”流程，彻底解决部署异常时产生幽灵文件夹及数据库残留的问题。</li>
          <li>[优化] 深度重构身份验证架构，采用六层解耦设计，显著提升微软及 Xbox 登录稳定性。</li>
          <li>[优化] 优化全局侧边栏布局与下载管理器 UI，大幅提升手柄操作下的信息密度与易用性。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>LAN Sync Support and Deployment Stability Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Implemented LAN device discovery, pairing, and trust management for seamless cross-device instance and save transfers.</li>
          <li>[New] Added background playtime tracking with real-time cross-device data synchronization.</li>
          <li>[New] Refactored Resource Center with integrated project search, dependency resolution, and one-click mod installation.</li>
          <li>[New] Introduced a new Wardrobe preview modal featuring 3D skin rendering and detailed customization.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Implemented Atomic Deployment workflow to ensure zero-residue cleanup on installation failures.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Architecturally refactored authentication logic using a decoupled six-layer design for enhanced stability.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Refined sidebar layout and download manager UI for improved information density and controller usability.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  
  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>
