<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.mrshell.PiLauncher</id>
  
  <name>PiLauncher</name>
  
  <summary>Minecraft Launcher for Gamepad</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_CN">专为手柄设计的 Minecraft 启动器</summary>

  <developer id="com.mrshell">
    <name>MrShell</name>
  </developer>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <description>
    <p xml:lang="zh_CN">PiLauncher 是一款为游戏手柄和掌机量身定制的 Minecraft 启动器。它拥有为主机式体验优化的全屏用户界面，让你可以轻松地使用手柄管理、配置和运行你的 Minecraft 游戏实例。</p>
    <p>PiLauncher is a Minecraft launcher tailored for gamepads and handheld consoles. It features a full-screen, console-like user interface optimized for controller inputs, allowing you to easily manage and launch your Minecraft instances.</p>
    <ul>
      <li xml:lang="zh_CN">完全支持手柄操作，提供沉浸式大屏体验。</li>
      <li>Full gamepad support for an immersive large-screen experience.</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh_CN">自动识别和配置手柄相关模组。</li>
      <li>Automatic detection and configuration of gamepad-related mods.</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh_CN">极简且现代化的实例和模组管理。</li>
      <li>Minimalist and modern instance and mod management.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.mrshell.PiLauncher.desktop</launchable>

  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
  </categories>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.1.26" date="2026-04-18">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">功能增强与体验优化</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 实现基于 CAS 的 Mod 快照与回滚系统，支持查看详细的文件变更差异。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 新增服务器绑定功能，支持在实例详情中关联特定服务器并设置自动加入。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 新增「联机中心」页面，整合社区服务器目录与认证直连入口。</li>
          <li>[优化] 深度优化第三方实例导入兼容性，修复了多级版本继承链的加载逻辑。</li>
          <li>[优化] 重构实例详情面板，将基础信息、自定义链接及维护操作等模块化解耦。</li>
          <li>[优化] 增强全局焦点捕获与导航记忆机制，大幅提升手柄操作的交互连贯性。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Feature Enhancements and UX Optimizations</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Implemented CAS-based Mod Snapshot and Rollback system with detailed file diffing.</li>
          <li>[New] Added Server Binding feature, allowing instances to be linked to specific servers with auto-join support.</li>
          <li>[New] Introduced Multiplayer hub for community server discovery and direct connections.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Improved compatibility for third-party instance imports with recursive version loading.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Refactored Instance Detail panel into modular components for better maintainability.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Enhanced global focus management and navigation persistence for a smoother gamepad experience.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>
